[Music]
Hello everyone and welcome back
to English Pot. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we
are covering a very important health issue.
That's right. We
are, that's right.
In case of an emergency,
maybe somebody stops breathing,
so we need to apply CPR.
Now what is this procedure?
Well, let's take a
look at it in vocabulary
preview. Vocabulary preview.
CPR in English is an acronym.
That means C, P and R all
stand for different words.
The big freeze here is cardio
pulmonary resuscitation.
All right, so you don't
have to remember that.
Well, it's pretty hard.
What if you break it down?
So what is cardio?
Cardio means it has to do
with your heart. And then
pulmonary? Pulmonary means lungs.
It has to do with your lungs
and what about resuscitation.
That means to bring back.
So to resuscitate is to
bring back to life. That's right.
Okay, so this is a very
popular procedure.
You probably see it in movies
when you know somebody
almost drowned the
lifeguard perform CPR.
Oh no, the love of my life is
just drowned and then someone
comes and they
push their chest. Right.
There's a one, two, three,
they count. And then the person
spits out water and
everything. And they're like,
all right, he's loved too.
All right, so that's CPR.
Why don't we listen to this dialogue, see
what's going on and we'll be back shortly.
Hello, everyone. And
welcome to our CPR for
Beginners course. First
of all, does anyone know
what CPR stands for? Cardio
pulmonary resuscitation.
That's right. We apply
CPR in the case of cardiac
arrest or pulmonary arrest.
What does that mean?
Well, basically, if your
heart stops pumping blood
or your lungs stop
pumping air, then we need to
get them going again. That's when
we have to apply this procedure.
Let's begin. I need
a volunteer. Me.
Me. All right, come here
and lay flat on your back.
Let's suppose this young
woman has stopped breathing.
We must lift the
person's chin so that we
clear a pathway for
air to get into the lungs.
Then we place our mouth
over the other person's mouth
and blow air two or
three times like this.
Wait, what are you doing?
I'm a married woman.
You can't just try to kiss
me like that. Ma'am, I'm not
trying to kiss you. I'm
trying to demonstrate how to
apply CPR in the case of
an emergency. Well, okay.
No French kissing. As I was saying, we
blow air through the mouth in this manner.
Once this is done, we must
try to get the heart going again.
To do this, we place our
hands over the person's
chest and press down
firmly two or three times.
Wait, what are you doing? You can't
just kiss me then go for second base.
All right, we're back. So a couple of
pretty difficult words and phrases there,
but don't worry. We'll explain
them now in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
The first phrase we've got
today is cardiac arrest.
All right, so cardiac
arrest now cardiac. I
think that has to do with
the heart again, right?
Exactly. Your heart.
And what about arrest? Well, arrest means
two things. Maybe you've heard of this
meaning to arrest somebody.
The police arrested someone.
Well, this means
to stop to stop.
Okay. So we're not talking
about the police here.
We're talking about
the heart stopping.
Okay. So cardiac arrest
means when your heart stops.
Okay. And another
word that's right next to
it, pulmonary arrest.
So I'm guessing again,
pulmonary has to do
with lungs. That's right.
And arrest stops so your
lungs stop pumping air.
Exactly. So cardiac
and pulmonary arrest,
these are two times when
your heart or your lungs,
they stop doing what
they are supposed to do.
All right. And interestingly
enough, the heart
pumps blood, the lungs pump
air, and that's our next word.
What is this word to
pump? To pump means
to fill something with.
Okay. So for example,
the heart pumps blood
to the rest of your body.
That means it's always
making sure your body has
blood going into it. And
the same thing with your
lungs, your lungs help oxygen and air get
to the rest of your body. So they pump it.
They fill up with air. Okay. And
we can do the same in other things.
For example, you
pump air into your tire.
That's right. If you
have a flat tire, you're
riding your bicycle and
your bicycle won't move.
Oh, no, you have to
pump it with air. That means
fill it up with air. Okay.
Or maybe even pump
water, right, making your
house. Or pump your car up
with gas. Okay. All right.
Very good. So now the man
is going to explain how to
perform this procedure CPR.
And he asks for a
volunteer. Okay. A volunteer.
This is a word that
can be both a noun.
So a thing. And it can
be an action of her. Okay.
So who is or what is a
volunteer? A volunteer is
someone who offers to
do something for free for
free without you asking
them to do it. Right. So
are there any volunteers
in the room? Right.
And so I want to
store this on the board.
Me. Me. I do. Okay.
You can also volunteer
to help people who
need help. So for example,
in Haiti, there's an
earthquake. And there are many
people who offered to
volunteer to help patients.
So that means they said, I will work for
free to help these people of volunteer.
They volunteer or to
volunteer. Very good.
So now we have our volunteer
and the man is explaining what to do.
Lift the person's chin so that we clear
a pathway for air to get into the lungs.
Oh, this is a good one.
So a path is like a road.
It's where something can go, can move, to
clear a pathway means to make some room.
Okay. Clear path. So
that means think about it.
If you can't breathe,
someone has to find a way
to make room to make
a hole for you to breathe.
So that means to move
whatever is blocking you
to clear some kind of
space. Okay. So that's a
pathway, a clear space. And
now well, he's demonstrating
how to perform CPR. So what
is this verb to demonstrate?
To demonstrate
is very important.
We use this in most kinds of
teaching. So to demonstrate
is to show or to give
an example. Okay.
So for example here in English
pod, we are demonstrating
how to use these words
in sentences. Exactly.
So an example is a good
way to demonstrate the
the word or the phrase.
Very good. All right.
Why don't we listen to
this dialogue again and we'll
be back in a bit.
Hello, everyone.
And welcome to our CPR for
Beginners course. First of all,
does anyone know what CPR stands
for? Cardiopulmonary resuscitation.
That's right. We apply CPR in the case
of cardiac arrest or pulmonary arrest.
What does that mean?
Well, basically, if your
heart stops pumping
blood or your lung stop
pumping air, then we need
to get them going again.
That's when we have
to apply this procedure.
Let's begin. I need a
volunteer. Me. Me. All right.
Come here and lay flat
on your back. Let's suppose
this young woman
has stopped breathing.
We must lift the person's
chin so that we clear a pathway
for air to get into the
lungs. Then we place
our mouth over the other
person's mouth and blow
air two or three times like
this. Wait, what are you doing?
I'm a married
woman. You can't just
try to kiss me like that. Ma'am,
I'm not trying to kiss you.
I'm trying to demonstrate how to apply CPR
in the case of an emergency. Well, okay.
No French kissing. As I
was saying, we blow air
through the mouth in this
manner. Once this is done,
we must try to get
the heart going again.
To do this, we place our
hands over the person's chest
and press down firmly
two or three times.
Wait, what are you doing?
You can't just kiss me then go
for second base.
All right, we're back.
So now let's go with fluency
builder. Fluency builder.
Well, the first phrase
in fluency builder we
hear in the beginning
of today's dialogue,
the teacher says, well,
basically, if your heart
stops pumping blood, then
we need to get it going again.
Okay. So that's a whole
phrase there to get
something going to get it
going. What do you mean by this?
This means to start
it up again. Okay.
So we could say, I used
to teach an English class
for my colleagues, but
we stopped having it.
I'd like to get it going
again. Okay. So you'd like to
start it up again. Exactly.
So usually you're talking
about turning something on
or getting something started.
For example, maybe
your car won't start.
So if you push it,
you can get it going.
Right. To get it going or to
turn the key is to get it going.
Okay. Right. So to
get something going.
Now moving on, we have two key phrases
here that are a little bit spicy, right?
Yeah, they're very romantic.
Although it shouldn't
be very romantic. All right.
Well, this phrase that we
have coming up is French
kiss to French kiss
someone or a French kiss.
So the volunteer says,
okay, I'm happy to help you,
but no French kissing. Okay.
So what is French kissing?
No one wants to answer. All right. What
is it? Well, it is when you kiss someone,
but your tongue goes into
that other person's mouth.
All right. So there's
a normal kiss.
You can kiss your
friends on the cheek, but
a French kiss means
that you use your tongue.
Okay. So I wonder why they call it a French
kiss. Maybe Americans just were too shy.
They blamed it on the French. Maybe
the French listeners out there can tell us.
All right. So now moving
on and she says, okay,
no French kissing. Now the
man is going to perform CPR.
And obviously he has
to firmly press down on
her chest to get her heart
pumping blood, right?
Right. This is a part of
CPR. So first of all, you
try to give the person
air so they can breathe.
And then you have to push
their chest to start their heart.
And this woman,
the volunteer says,
hey, what are you doing? You can't just
kiss me first and then go for second base.
All right. So what is
second base? Okay.
This is a sports metaphor
with baseball, right?
Baseball has four bases. First, second,
third base and home plate or exactly.
So in romance, and
we're talking about dating,
we have a way to say first,
second, third and fourth base.
First base is kissing.
That's kissing, right?
So second base
would be second base.
Well, in this example, it
means touching touching
certain parts of the
body romantic touching.
All right. So second base.
And then obviously we
have third and fourth, but we're
not going to get to that man.
You can look it
up on Google, third
base and fourth base. We
trust that you can find it.
But first and second
base are very common.
It's it's okay to talk
about. It's not a bad word.
So you'll probably
see it in movies.
Young kids talking about first base
or going to second base with someone.
So it's kind of saying this in a
different way as a metaphor, as you said,
it's more polite than
talking about. All right.
So that's all the words
and phrases we have
on fluency, brother. Let's listen
to this great dialogue one last time.
Hello, everyone, and
welcome to our CPR for
Beginners course. First
of all, does anyone know
what CPR stands for?
Cardiopulmonary resuscitation.
That's right. We
apply CPR in the case
of cardiac arrest
or pulmonary arrest.
What does that mean?
Well, basically, if your heart
stops pumping blood or
your lung stop pumping
air, then we need to
get them going again.
That's when we have
to apply this procedure.
Let's begin. I need
a volunteer. Me. Me.
All right. Come here
and lay flat on your back.
Let's suppose this young
woman has stopped breathing.
We must lift the
person's chin so that
we clear a pathway for
air to get into the lungs.
Then we place our mouth
over the other person's
mouth and blow air two
or three times like this.
Wait, what are you doing?
I'm a married woman.
You can't just try
to kiss me like that.
Ma'am, I'm not trying
to kiss you. I'm trying to
demonstrate how to apply
CPR in the case of an emergency.
Well, okay. No French kissing.
As I was saying, we blow
air through the mouth
and this manner. Once
this is done, we must
try to get the heart
going again. To do this,
we place our hands over the person's chest
and press down firmly two or three times.
Wait, what are you doing? You can't
just kiss me then go for second base.
All right, we're
back. So a CPR class.
This is actually a very
popular thing to take up.
You never know when you
need to perform it, right?
That's true. And I
think it's a really smart
smart class to take.
You can usually take
them for free at a community
center or a fire department.
The Red Cross. The Red Cross.
I have a Red Cross
certification. Oh, really?
So you know how to perform
this? Yep. Wow. It's actually,
as I said, I think it
would be very useful and
I've never taken a course like this up,
but I know how to perform the procedure.
So I'm not certified though. So
I'm not a certified CPR person.
But it's interesting.
Let us know if in your
country, maybe you can
take CPR classes or maybe
you're a CPR certified
technician or maybe you
are trained in other ways. So
we're curious about those as well.
Let us know if you
have any questions
about today's lesson or our
website is EnglishPod.com.
All right, we'll see you
guys there. Bye, everyone.